Guide to the Arthur Jeffery Papers
Rare Book and Manuscript Library Columbia University Libraries
Arthur Jeffery Papers
[ca. 1920]-1959.
Jeffery, Arthur.
32 linear ft. (62 document boxes and 2 flat boxes).
Columbia University. Rare Book and Manuscript Library, New York, NY.
MS#0674
4078954
Arthur Jeffery (1892-1959) was Professor of Semitic languages at Columbia University from 1938 until his death. This collection of manuscripts, typescripts, manuscript notes and typescript notes with some related correspondence reflects Jeffery's research and writing on the vocabulary and history of the text of the Koran.
History
Arthur Jeffery (1892-1959) was Professor of Semitic languages at Columbia University from 1938 until his death. His professional life was spent conducting historical studies of Middle Eastern manuscripts. Jeffrey is perhaps best know for his books Materials for the history of the text of the Qur'an: the old codices and The Foreign Vocabulary of the Qur'an, which traces the origins of 318 foreign (non-Arabic) words found in the Qur'an. Some of Jeffery's studies are included in The Origins of The Koran: Classic Essays on Islam's Holy Book, edited by Ibn Warraq.
Scope and Content
Manuscripts, typescripts, manuscript notes, and typescript notes with some related correspondence reflecting Jeffery's research and writing on the vocabulary and history of the text of the Qu'ran. There are also materials on Islam, pre-Islamic Arabia, Semitic religions and languages, Christianity, the Eastern Churches, the Bible, the Dead Sea Scrolls, Gnosticism, general religion, and theology.
Subjects
Jeffery, Arthur.; Arabic language--Foreign words and phrases.; Arabic literature--Translations into English.; Semites--Religion.; Islam.; Islamic literature.; Semitic languages--Research.; Christianity.; Eastern churches.; Gnosticism.; Middle Eastern philology.; Religion.; Theology.; College teachers.; Koran.; Bible.; Dead Sea scrolls.; Koran--Criticism, Textual.; Koran--Language, style.; Koran--Readings.
Access Restrictions
This collection has no restrictions.
The following boxes are located off-site: 1-52. You will need to request this material from the Rare Book and Manuscript Library at least twenty-four (24) hours in advance to use the collection in the Rare Book and Manuscript Library reading room.
Acquisition
1959 M-59 Jeffery, Mrs. Arthur Gift
Finding aid in repository
- Contents List
  - Photostats of Manuscript--Mingana Islamic Arabic, undated (Box 1)
  - Bibliographies of Quran Translations, undated (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Criticism and Translating the Quran, undated (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Text and Versions of the Quran, undated
    - A-D (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - E-F (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - G-M (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - N-Z (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - "Had Muhammad a Scripture Teacher?," undated (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Imala Concluding Essay, undated (Box 3)
  - Lecture Notes on Selected Quranic Passages, 1925 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Notes on Quranic Interpretation; Nöldeke-Schwally's Introduction of the Quran; Collation of Quran Texts of Hinckelmann, Marracio and Flügel Notebooks, undated (Box 4)
  - On The Translation of the Quran, 1936 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Pause, undated (Box 6)
  - Quranic Tractates; Jesus References; Rudolph, "Die Abhängigkeit des Qoran von Judenlhum und Christentum"; Quranisches Notebooks, undated (Box 7)
  - Variant WAQFs According to Al-Marandi (1337), undated (Box 8)
  - Quran Subject Index Files, undated
    - A (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - B-C (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - C-D (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - D-F (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - F-G (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - A-S (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Manichaean Doctrine, undated (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Manichaica, undated, (2 Folders) (Box 6, Folder 2-3)
  - Notes on Manichaeism, undated (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Pre-Islamic Arabia, undated (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Prolegomena to the Study of Islam, undated (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Writings of Mani and his Disciples, undated (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - A Reader on Islam, undated, (3 Folders) (Box 7, Folder 1-3)
  - Foreign Vocabulary of the Quran, The Typescript, pgs. 1-150, 1929 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - "Translation of Ibn Hisham" Manuscript, circa 1940 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Transliterations Lecture and Article Notes, undated (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Untitled Manuscript, undated (Box 8, Folder 5-7)
  - Armenian Language, Old Testament and Mesopotamia Typescripts, undated (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Baldawi; Ikhtilas; Kalila wa Dimna; Mutawakhili and Ath-Tha?labi Notebooks, undated (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Bergsträsser's "History of the Quran " and " Quran Readings Hasan of Basra" Notebooks, undated (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Cheiko's "Christianity in Arabia" and Weil's "Einleitung in Den Koran" Notebooks, undated (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Critical Text of Quran Notes, undated (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - "Dervish Prayer-Meeting: Glass Chewing and Sword Swallowing as a Spiritual Exercise" Typescript, undated (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - "Early Discussions About the Quran,"Muslim World, unknown author, undated (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - "Meccan Festival, The," Dr. T. Zaayer Thesis, 1880 (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - Near East Photostatic Map; Der Mastaba-Friedhof bei Gise Print; and Newsclippings, undated, 1951-1952, 1955, 1957 (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - "Oriental Christianity and the Origin of Islam" Typescript, undated (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - Quranic Monography and Quranic Studies Notebooks, undated (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - Semitic Epigraphy Charts, undated (Box 9, Folder 12)
  - Semitic Material in the Egyptian Excretion Texts Summaries, undated (Box 9, Folder 13)
  - Shanqiti on the Mu?allaquat Notebooks I-III, undated (Box 9, Folder 14)
  - Siyuti Itqan Notebooks I-II, undated (Box 9, Folder 15)
  - Tablet Fragment Photographs and Translation, undated (Box 9, Folder 16)
  - Taha Hussein on pre-Islamic Poetry Notebook, undated (Box 9, Folder 17)
  - Untitled Notebooks, undated (Box 9, Folder 18)
  - Analecta Qoranica, undated (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Bashshar B. Burd, undated (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Christology or Quran [Documents in I. Schlatter in EMM, 1918] Notebook, undated (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Commentary to Variants in Fatihah, undated (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence, undated, 1925, 1937 (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Eastern Churches, undated (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Gods of the Pagan Arabs, The, Notebook, Undated (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - Imala; Al-Jaza?iri on the Seven Ahruf; Lines of Tradition from the Seven According to Al-Mu?addil's Rand?atal-H?uhaz?; and Introduction to Quran Notes, undated (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - Religion in Pre-Islamic Arabia, undated (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - Quran and Arabic Notes, Misc., undated (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - Quran Translations and Correspondence, undated, 1934-1935 (Box 10, Folder 11)
  - Quranic References in Cosmology, undated (Box 10, Folder 12)
  - Salman Al-Farisi Background Information and Correspondence, undated, 1939-1940 (Box 10, Folder 13)
  - Sigla for Quran Readers Notebook, undated (Box 10, Folder 14)
  - Untitled Notebook and Clippings in Arabic, undated (Box 10, Folder 15)
  - Bartholomew of Edessa Notes, undated (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Comparative Semitic Grammar Notes, undated (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Canon and Text of the Old Testament Notebook, undated (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Interpretation of the Quran in Present Day Islam, undated (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - Logos Typescript, undated (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - "Muhammad's Doctrine of Revelation" Typescript, 1932 (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - Muqni? of ad-Dani Notebook, undated (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - Muslim Eschatology "Grand Assizes: A Description of the Last Trump," Typescript, undated (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - Muslim Eschatology Notes and Correspondence, undated, 1956 (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - Muslim Eschatology Notes and Correspondence, undated, 1957 (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - Notes on the Kabbalah, undated (Box 11, Folder 11)
  - Notes and Pamphlets, undated, 1928, 1952 (Box 11, Folder 12)
  - Quranic Material, Misc., undated (Box 11, Folder 13)
  - Quranic Orthography, undated (Box 11, Folder 14)
  - Syriac Grammar Exercises to Robinson's Grammar, undated (Box 11, Folder 15)
  - WAQF Positions According to Ushmuni's Manar Al-Huda (1286), undated (Box 11, Folder 16)
  - Arabic / English Vocabulary Notecards, undated (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - Bibliographic Notecards, undated (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - Conspectus of Editions of Arabic Text of the Quran, Notebooks 1-3, undated (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - Notes on Quranic Interpretation, undated (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - Quranic Readings Notecards (in Arabic), undated (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - Quranic Readings of Zaid b. Ali, undated (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - Alphabetical List of the Qurra (Readers of the Quran), undated
    - A (Box 13, Folder 1)
    - B-H (Box 13, Folder 2)
    - I-J (Box 13, Folder 3)
    - K-R (Box 13, Folder 4)
    - S-Z (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - Ambrosiana F289 Manuscript Photographs, undated (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - Literal Versions of the Themes in the Beirut Marad al-Klutut, undated (Box 13, Folder 7)
  - Untitled Notebooks, undated (Box 13, Folder 9)
  - Controversy, undated
    - General, (2 Folders) (Box 14, Folder 1-2)
    - A-H (Box 14, Folder 3)
    - J-K (Box 14, Folder 4)
    - L-Z (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - Sufism, undated
    - A-P (Box 14, Folder 6)
    - Q-Z (Box 14, Folder 7)
    - Printed Material, (2 Folders) (Box 14, Folder 8-9)
  - Aboth de Rabbi Nathan, 1942 (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - Alexander, Dhu 'L-Qarnain, undated (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - Alphabet, 1948-1954 (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - American Research Center (Egypt), 1948 (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - 'AMR-MEMRA, undated (Box 15, Folder 5)
  - Arabic Script, undated (Box 15, Folder 6)
  - Aramaic Scripts, 1948 (Box 15, Folder 7)
  - Dead Sea Scrolls, undated
    - Introduction (Box 15, Folder 8)
    - Research (Box 15, Folder 9)
  - Essay
    - "Corruption of the Tetragrammaton," 1940 (Box 15, Folder 10)
    - "Dominant Ideas in Islamic Culture Today," 1942 (Box 15, Folder 11)
  - Essay and Notes on the Kur'an, undated (Box 15, Folder 12)
  - Greek Religions, undated (Box 15, Folder 13)
  - Kufic Codices, undated
    - Berlin (Box 15, Folder 14)
    - British Museum (Box 15, Folder 15)
    - Gotha, Pertsch Katalog (Box 15, Folder 16)
    - Paris (Box 15, Folder 17)
    - Vienna, Copenhagen, Escorial (Box 15, Folder 18)
  - Maimonides, undated (Box 15, Folder 19)
  - Mystery Religions, undated (Box 15, Folder 20)
  - Subject Notes, A-Z, undated (Box 15, Folder F21)
  - Zoroastrianism, undated (Box 15, Folder 22)
  - Subject Notes, undated
    - A (Box 16, Folder 1)
    - B (Box 16, Folder 2)
    - C (Box 16, Folder 3)
    - D-F (Box 16, Folder 4)
    - G-J (Box 16, Folder 5)
    - K-M (Box 16, Folder 6)
    - N-Q (Box 17, Folder 1)
    - R-S (Box 17, Folder 2)
    - T-Z (Box 17, Folder 3)
  - Subject Notes, A-Z, undated (Box 17, Folder 4)
  - Subject Notes, Numerical, undated (Box 17, Folder 5)
  - Bibliography for Semitic Philology, undated (Box 18, Folder 1)
  - Early Syrian Arab and South Arabian Christianity and the Christology of the Quran, undated (Box 18, Folder 2)
  - Essay on the Cufic Quran in the Khedive Library in Cairo, undated (Box 18, Folder 3)
  - Essay on the Samarkand Kufic Quran, undated (Box 18, Folder 4)
  - Notebook on Nabataeans, undated (Box 18, Folder 5)
  - Notebook on Semitic Languages, undated, (2 Folders) (Box 18, Folder 6-7)
  - Notes on Folios with Original Writing, undated (Box 18, Folder 8)
  - Notes on Semitic Philology, undated (Box 18, Folder 9)
  - Notes Pertaining to Christianity, undated (Box 18, Folder 10)
  - Notes Pertaining to the Quran, undated (Box 18, Folder 11)
  - Churches, undated
    - Abyssinian (Box 19, Folder 1)
    - Armenian (Box 19, Folder 2)
    - Egyptian (Box 19, Folder 3)
    - Nestorian (Box 19, Folder 4)
    - Orthodoxy (Box 19, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence, 1935-1959 (Box 19, Folder 6)
  - Katan and the Mu'tazila Groups, undated (Box 19, Folder 7)
  - Microfilm--E.Littmann, Thamud und Safa, undated (Box 19, Folder 8)
  - Modern Egyptian Arabic, 1922 (Box 19, Folder 9)
  - Postcards and Maps, undated (Box 19, Folder 10)
  - Subject Notecards, I-M, undated (Box 20, Folder 1)
  - Author and Subject Notecards, undated (Box 21, Folder 1)
  - First Sura of the Quran in Different Languages, undated (Box 21, Folder 2)
  - Subject Notecards, undated
    - A-D (Box 21, Folder 3)
    - E-I (Box 21, Folder 4)
    - J-O (Box 21, Folder 5)
    - P-S (Box 21, Folder 6)
    - T-Z (Box 21, Folder 7)
  - Vocabulary in Arabic, undated (Box 21, Folder 8)
  - Vocabulary Notecards, undated
    - A-K (Box 21, Folder 9)
    - M-Z (Box 21, Folder 10)
  - Dead Sea Scrolls, 1956 (Box 22, Folder 1)
  - History of Religion, undated (Box 22, Folder 2)
  - Islamic History Lecture Notes, undated (Box 22, Folder 3)
  - Manuscript on Muhammad and the Quran, undated, (2 Folders) (Box 22, Folder 4-5)
  - Natural Philosophy, undated (Box 22, Folder 6)
  - South Arabian Inscriptions, undated (Box 22, Folder 7)
  - Umar II and Leo III Correspondence, undated (Box 22, Folder 8)
  - Photostats of Arabic Manuscripts, undated, (4 Folders) (Box 23, Folder 1-4)
  - Photostats of Arabic Manuscripts--Meknes, undated (Box 23, Folder 5)
  - Armenian Foundation, undated (Box 24, Folder 1)
  - Australian Aborigines, 1952-1957 (Box 24, Folder 2)
  - Ayyub, undated (Box 24, Folder 3)
  - Babylonian Religion, undated (Box 24, Folder 4)
  - Beha'ism, 1955 (Box 24, Folder 5)
  - Byzantine Arabia, undated (Box 24, Folder 6)
  - Camel, 1944-1955 (Box 24, Folder 7)
  - Canaanite Religion, 1944 (Box 24, Folder 8)
  - Coptic Gnostic Papyri, 1952-1956 (Box 24, Folder 9)
  - Crete (Minoan), 1954-1958 (Box 24, Folder 10)
  - Crusades, 1951 (Box 24, Folder 11)
  - Dervish Orders, undated (Box 24, Folder 12)
  - Dhu'n-nun al-Misri, undated (Box 24, Folder 13)
  - Druses of Lebanon, undated (Box 24, Folder 14)
  - Egyptian Religion, undated (Box 24, Folder 15)
  - False Messiahs, undated (Box 24, Folder 16)
  - Feasts and Festivals, 1951 (Box 24, Folder 17)
  - Ghassanids, 1955-1957 (Box 24, Folder 18)
  - Gilgamesh, undated (Box 24, Folder 19)
  - Gnosticism, undated (Box 24, Folder 20)
  - Harris Foundation, 1942 (Box 24, Folder 21)
  - Hinduism, 1958 (Box 24, Folder 22)
  - Hittites, undated (Box 24, Folder 23)
  - Houtsma Steenwerper, undated (Box 24, Folder 24)
  - Hyksos, 1956 (Box 24, Folder 25)
  - Islamic History, 1940-1956 (Box 24, Folder 26)
  - Jannes and Jambres, undated (Box 24, Folder 27)
  - Jesus in Islam, undated (Box 24, Folder 28)
  - Karaites, undated (Box 24, Folder 29)
  - Lakhmids of Al-Hira, undated (Box 24, Folder 30)
  - Lamaism, undated (Box 24, Folder 31)
  - Letter of Abgar, 1946 (Box 24, Folder 32)
  - Lihyanites, undated (Box 24, Folder 33)
  - Mandaeans, undated (Box 25, Folder 1)
  - Mecca, 1956 (Box 25, Folder 2)
  - Mi'Raj, undated (Box 25, Folder 3)
  - Mithraism, undated (Box 25, Folder 4)
  - Modern Movements in Islam, 1952 (Box 25, Folder 5)
  - Muhammadan Jurisprudence, undated (Box 25, Folder 6)
  - Nabataeans, 1956-1959 (Box 25, Folder 7)
  - North Arabian Languages, undated (Box 25, Folder 8)
  - Philosophy in Islam, undated (Box 25, Folder 9)
  - Quranic Exegesis, undated (Box 25, Folder 10)
  - Quranic Notes, undated (Box 25, Folder 11)
  - Roman Arabia, undated (Box 25, Folder 12)
  - Saint Thomas and India, undated (Box 25, Folder 13)
  - Samaritans, undated (Box 25, Folder 14)
  - Saracenic Civilization, undated (Box 25, Folder 15)
  - Serpent Worship, 1945 (Box 25, Folder 16)
  - Sects of Islam, 1957 (Box 25, Folder 17)
  - Seth, Shatil, Sethians, undated (Box 25, Folder 18)
  - Seven Sleepers, undated (Box 25, Folder 19)
  - Shadhiliyya, undated (Box 25, Folder 20)
  - Shamanism, undated (Box 25, Folder 21)
  - Shathiyyat, undated (Box 25, Folder 22)
  - Sinai, 1952-1959 (Box 25, Folder 23)
  - Slavery, undated (Box 25, Folder 24)
  - South Arabian Culture, 1950-1951 (Box 25, Folder 25)
  - Torah in Islam, undated (Box 25, Folder 26)
  - Vanished Tribes, undated (Box 25, Folder 27)
  - Wahhabism, undated (Box 25, Folder 28)
  - Water of Life, undated (Box 25, Folder 29)
  - Writing, 1957 (Box 25, Folder 30)
  - Yezidi, undated (Box 25, Folder 31)
  - Loose Notes, undated (Box 26, Folder 1)
  - Printed Materials
    - General, 1906-1952, (2 Folders) (Box 26, Folder 2-3)
    - Journals, 1916-1953, (2 Folders) (Box 26, Folder 4-5)
    - Reprints, 1915-1956, (2 Folders) (Box 26, Folder 6-7)
  - Indo-Iranian Philology, 1937-1950, (2 Folders) (Box 27, Folder 1-2)
  - Journals, 1939-1952 (Box 27, Folder 3)
  - Journals (Non-English languages), 1928-1938, (2 Folders) (Box 27, Folder 4-5)
  - Loose Notes, undated (Box 27, Folder 6)
  - Printed Materials
    - General, undated (Box 28, Folder 1)
    - Film Literature, undated (Box 28, Folder 2)
    - Journals and Reprints, 1926-1937 (Box 28, Folder 3)
    - Journals and Reprints, 1939 (Box 28, Folder 4)
    - Journals and Reprints, 1931-1945 (Box 28, Folder 5)
    - Newspaper Clippings, 1890-1899 (Box 28, Folder 6)
    - Pre-Muslim Arabia, 1940-1946 (Box 28, Folder 7)
    - Languages of Abyssinia, 1938-1958, (2 Folders) (Box 29, Folder 1-2)
    - Muslim Eschatology, 1948-1958 (Box 29, Folder 3)
    - Quranic Studies, 1928-1954, (2 Folders) (Box 29, Folder 4-5)
    - Semitic Antiquities, 1950 (Box 29, Folder 6)
    - Semitic Epigraphy, 1938-1954 (Box 29, Folder 7)
    - Buddhism and Christianity Compared, 1923-1924 (Box 30, Folder 1)
    - Muslim Hadith, 1938-1939 (Box 30, Folder 2)
    - Quranic Studies, 1934-1941 (Box 30, Folder 3)
    - Semitic Epigraphy, 1903-1950, (2 Folders) (Box 30, Folder 4-5)
    - Septuagint Studies, Books of the Bible, 1927-1957, (2 Folders) (Box 30, Folder 6-7)
  - Subject Files, undated
    - Aa-An (Box 31, Folder 1)
    - An-Az (Box 31, Folder 2)
    - B (Box 31, Folder 3)
    - C (Box 32, Folder 1)
    - Da-De (Box 32, Folder 2)
    - De-Du (Box 32, Folder 3)
    - E (Box 32, Folder 4)
    - F (Box 32, Folder 5)
    - G (Box 33, Folder 1)
    - Ha-He (Box 33, Folder 2)
    - He-Hy (Box 33, Folder 3)
    - I (Box 33, Folder 4)
    - J (Box 33, Folder 5)
    - K-Ma (Box 34, Folder 1)
    - Ma-Mi (Box 34, Folder 2)
    - Mi-My (Box 34, Folder 3)
    - N-O (Box 34, Folder 4)
    - Pac-Par (Box 34, Folder 5)
    - Par-Ps (Box 34, Folder 6)
    - Ps-Q (Box 35, Folder 1)
    - R (Box 35, Folder 2)
    - Sa-Se (Box 35, Folder 3)
    - Sh-Sz (Box 35, Folder 4)
    - Ta-Tr (Box 35, Folder 5)
  - Subject Notes, undated
    - T-U (Box 36, Folder 1)
    - V (Box 36, Folder 2)
    - W (Box 36, Folder 3)
    - X-Z (Box 36, Folder 4)
  - Quranic References Notecards, undated
    - A (Box 36, Folder 5)
    - B-H (Box 36, Folder 6)
    - I-M (Box 36, Folder 7)
    - N-S (Box 36, Folder 8)
    - T-Z (Box 36, Folder 9)
  - Subject Notes, 1959
    - A-I (Box 36, Folder 10)
    - J-Z (Box 36, Folder 11)
  - Arab Influences on Culture and Words Notes, undated (Box 37, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, 1935-1958 (Box 37, Folder 2)
  - "Eschatological Midrashim in Jellinek's Beth Ha-Midrash," Dissertation by Herman J. Fine, 1949 June (Box 37, Folder 3)
  - Geology School Notebook, undated (Box 37, Folder 4)
  - "Jewish Community in Egypt During the Twelfth Century," Dissertation by Abraham N. Zuroff, 1948 (Box 37, Folder 5)
  - Life of Mohammad from Original Sources, The, by A. Sprenger, MD, 1851 (Box 37, Folder 6)
  - Lord's Prayer, The, Various Languages, undated (Box 37, Folder 7)
  - "Muhammed ?Abdu's Critique of Christianity and Defense of Islam with His Suggestions for the Renaissance of Islam," Dissertation by John G. Lorimer, undated (Box 37, Folder 8)
  - "Manuscrits Orientaux" List, undated (Box 37, Folder 9)
  - "Pseudo-Philo's Saul and The Rabbis' Messiah Ben Ephraim," by Abram Spiro, 1952 (Box 37, Folder 10)
  - "Study of Foreign Words Occurring in the Hebrew and Aramaic of the Old Testament, A," by Maximillian Ellenbogen, undated (Box 37, Folder 11)
  - "Summer Journey to Al-Maghrib Al-Aqsa, A," Typescript with Photographs, [Travel Magazine], circa 1931 (Box 37, Folder 12)
  - Arabic Grammar, 1922 (Box 38, Folder 1)
  - Faculty, 1938-1946 (Box 38, Folder 2)
  - Notes on Christianity, undated (Box 38, Folder 3)
  - Notes on Chronology, Geography, and Language, undated (Box 38, Folder 4)
  - Pater Noster, undated (Box 38, Folder 5)
  - Photostat of Zahiriya Manuscript, undated (Box 38, Folder 6)
  - Printed Material
    - Non-Published, undated (Box 38, Folder 7)
    - Published, 1936-1939 (Box 38, Folder 8)
  - Speeches and Writing, 1956-1957 (Box 38, Folder 9)
  - Farquhar, J.N., Dr., Lectures on the Religions of India, Lecture I-VIII Outlines, undated (Box 39, Folder 1)
  - Introduction to Quran, Parts I-IV, undated (Box 39, Folder 2)
  - "K??ur?an" Typescript, undated (Box 39, Folder 3)
  - Nubian Christianity and Modern Theories of Religion Manuscripts, undated (Box 39, Folder 4)
  - "Qira?at, The," Manuscript undated (Box 39, Folder 5)
  - Quran Editions, Translations, Articles, undated, (2 Folders) (Box 39, Folder 6-7)
  - Quran Notebook #2, undated (Box 39, Folder 8)
  - Rowe, Alan, "Excavations in Palestine" and "Discoveries at Beth-Shan During the 1926 Season" Typescripts, 1920s (Box 39, Folder 9)
  - Arabic, Ethiopic and Germanic Vocabularies Notebooks, undated (Box 40, Folder 1)
  - Dvorák, Rudolf, "Fremdwörter (Foreign Words)" Notebook, undated (Box 40, Folder 2)
  - Hebrew Commentaries on the Story of Joseph Typescript, 1928 (Box 40, Folder 3)
  - Goldziher, "The Most Primitive Stage of Quran Interpretation," undated (Box 40, Folder 4)
  - Pre-Islamic Arabia Notes, Notebooks and Journal Articles, undated, 1921, (2 Folders) (Box 40, Folder 5-6)
  - Psalms Translations Notebook, undated (Box 40, Folder 7)
  - Quran Commentaries, Known Authors, undated, 1921, 1932 (Box 40, Folder 8)
  - Quran Commentaries, Unknown Authors, undated (Box 40, Folder 9)
  - Quranic Introduction and Islam Bibliographies, undated (Box 40, Folder 10)
  - Biblical Armaic Grammar, Elementary Exercise Course, undated (Box 41, Folder 1)
  - Early Palestinian Religion, undated (Box 41, Folder 2)
  - Foreign Words in the Quran, undated (Box 41, Folder 3)
  - Glossary of Quranic Names, undated (Box 41, Folder 4)
  - Notes on Greek Language Study, undated (Box 41, Folder 5)
  - Notes on Hamitic Philology, undated (Box 41, Folder 6)
  - Semitic Epigraphy I, undated (Box 41, Folder 7)
  - Semitic Religions--Hymns and Psalms, undated (Box 41, Folder 8)
  - Story of the Building of the Ka'bal, undated (Box 41, Folder 9)
  - Tha'labi's Account of Creation, undated (Box 41, Folder 10)
  - Clippings and Notes on Archaeological Findings, 1943-1959 (Box 42, Folder 1)
  - Early Phoenician Inscriptions, undated (Box 42, Folder 2)
  - History of Semitic Religion, undated (Box 42, Folder 3)
  - Inscriptions, undated (Box 42, Folder 4)
  - Lectures on Islam, undated (Box 42, Folder 5)
  - Notes on Talmud and Midrash, undated (Box 42, Folder 6)
  - Reading Lists, undated (Box 42, Folder 7)
  - Semitic Religions, undated (Box 42, Folder 8)
  - Adi B. Zaid, undated (Box 43, Folder 1)
  - Fundamentalism in Islam, undated (Box 43, Folder 2)
  - Hanif, undated (Box 43, Folder 3)
  - Islam, undated (Box 43, Folder 4)
  - Lecture Notes on Islamic Civilization, undated (Box 43, Folder 5)
  - Lecture Notes on the Religion of Islam, undated (Box 43, Folder 6)
  - Muhammad, undated (Box 43, Folder 7)
  - Notes on AD Dani Al Quatudi, undated (Box 43, Folder 8)
  - Notes on Islam and the Quran, undated (Box 43, Folder 9)
  - Prophets in Islam, undated (Box 43, Folder 10)
  - Summary of Quranic Theology, undated (Box 43, Folder 11)
  - Writings on Islam, undated (Box 43, Folder 12)
  - Lecture Notes on Islamic Theology, (2 Folders) (Box 44, Folder 2-3)
  - Lecture Notes on Dervishism, undated (Box 44, Folder 4)
  - Greek Textbook Notes, 1915-1916 (Box 44, Folder 5)
  - Notes on the Kamil of Mubarrad, undated (Box 44, Folder 6)